Mss.Rec.125 Mss.Rec.125
American Philosophical Society
- Audio recordings
  - Concerning the League: Onondaga to English, page 373 to 380, 1971-05-18; 26-01; 1.0 .mp3; 01:36:30; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Gibson, John Arthur, 1849-1912; Goldenweiser, Alexander, 1880-1940; Skye, James
    A translation of the Onondaga text of the Deganawidah epic as given in 1912 by Chief John A. Gibson and transcribed by Alexander Goldenweiser. This program alternates frequently between two forms of interaction. The first is the re-playing of previously recorded readings of short segments of the Onondaga text by William Fenton and Howard Sky, which is followed by the re-reading of the Onondaga text by Fenton, with English translation given by James Skye. Includes occasional discussion in English. There is consistent uncorrected background noise throughout the recording.
  - Concerning the League: Onondaga to English, page 380 to 387, 1971-05-18; 26-02; 1.0 .mp3; 01:36:35; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Gibson, John Arthur, 1849-1912; Goldenweiser, Alexander, 1880-1940; Skye, James
  - Concerning the League: Onondaga to English, page 387 to 393, 1971-05-20; 27-01; 1.0 .mp3; 01:36:24; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Gibson, John Arthur, 1849-1912; Goldenweiser, Alexander, 1880-1940; Skye, James
    A translation of the Onondaga text of the Deganawidah epic as given in 1912 by Chief John A. Gibson and transcribed by Alexander Goldenweiser. This program alternates frequently between two forms of interaction. The first is the re-playing of previously recorded readings of short segments of the Onondaga text by William Fenton and Howard Sky, which is followed by the re-reading of the Onondaga text by Fenton, with English translation given by James Skye. Includes occasional discussion in English. Sound levels periodically fluctuate throughout the recording.
  - Concerning the League: Onondaga text, page 387 to 394, 1971-05-20; 27-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:25:11; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Gibson, John Arthur, 1849-1912; Goldenweiser, Alexander, 1880-1940; Skye, James
  - Concerning the League: Onondaga text, page 395 to 401, 1971-05-20; 27-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:19:24; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Gibson, John Arthur, 1849-1912; Goldenweiser, Alexander, 1880-1940; Skye, James
  - Concerning the League: Onondaga to English, page 393 to 399, 1971-05-21; 28-01; 1.0 .mp3; 01:36:15; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Gibson, John Arthur, 1849-1912; Goldenweiser, Alexander, 1880-1940; Skye, James
  - Concerning the League: Onondaga to English, page 399 to 401, 1971-05-21; 28-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:34:19; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Gibson, John Arthur, 1849-1912; Goldenweiser, Alexander, 1880-1940; Skye, James
  - Concerning the League: Onondaga text, page 401 to 410, 1971-09-16; 29-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:59:03; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Gibson, John Arthur, 1849-1912; Goldenweiser, Alexander, 1880-1940; Skye, James
  - Concerning the League: Onondaga text, page 417 to end, 1971-09-16; 29-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:35; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Gibson, John Arthur, 1849-1912; Goldenweiser, Alexander, 1880-1940; Skye, James
  - Concerning the League: Onondaga to English, page 401 to 404, 1971-09-16; 30-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:41:56; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Gibson, John Arthur, 1849-1912; Goldenweiser, Alexander, 1880-1940; Skye, James
  - Concerning the League: Onondaga to English, page 404 to 410, 1971-09-16; 30-02; 1.0 .mp3; 02:06:14; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Gibson, John Arthur, 1849-1912; Goldenweiser, Alexander, 1880-1940; Skye, James
  - Concerning the League: Onondaga to English, page 410 to 417, 1971-09-16; 30-03; 1.0 .mp3; 01:35:10; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Gibson, John Arthur, 1849-1912; Goldenweiser, Alexander, 1880-1940; Skye, James
  - Concerning the League: Onondaga to English, page 417 to 425, 1971-09-16; 30-04; 1.0 .mp3; 01:36:05; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Gibson, John Arthur, 1849-1912; Goldenweiser, Alexander, 1880-1940; Skye, James
  - Concerning the League: Onondaga to English, page 425 to end, 1971-09-18; 31-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:35:24; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Gibson, John Arthur, 1849-1912; Goldenweiser, Alexander, 1880-1940; Skye, James
  - Discussion of kinship terms in Ganonhsyoni ge'ah text, 1971-09-18; 31-02; 1.0 .mp3; 01:47:09; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Skye, James
    Brantford (Ont.); Deganawida; Iroquois Indians--History; Onondaga Indians--Kinship; Onondaga language--Texts